A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, New Delhi, India, RG 6, SG 7 FA396
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs, 1955-1973, n.d.; I4; 57 __Boxes __21.4 cubic feet
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Seed Development, 1959-1973, n.d.; I4.04
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Seed Reports and Attachments, 1960-1964, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 437)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Seed Reports and Attachments, 1960-1964, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 438)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Seed Reports and Attachments, 1960-1964, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 439)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - Freeman, Wayne H., September 1961-October 1965, January 1967 (Box 66, Folder 440)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - Johnson, A. A., October 1960-April 1961 (Box 66, Folder 441)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - Renfro, B. L., August-September 1961 (Box 66, Folder 442)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - Sprague, Ernest W., July-August 1961 (Box 66, Folder 443)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - Traywick, Jack Dee, September 1961-September 1964 (Box 66, Folder 444)
    - Reports (Printed) - All India Seed Testing Workshop Proceedings, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 445)
    - Reports (Printed) - Improved Agricultural Seeds, 1960, 1962; 2 volumes (Box 67, Folder 446)
    - Reports (Printed) - The Lebanese Seed Program (Draft), 1972 (Box 67, Folder 447)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings - First All India Symposium on Improved Seed Equipment, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 448)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of Seed Specialists' Seminar, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 449)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings - Seed Improvement Training Courses - Volume 1, 1965-1966 (Box 68, Folder 450)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings - Seed Improvement Training Courses - Volume 2, 1965-1966 (Box 69, Folder 451)
    - Reports (Printed) - Seed Certification Manual, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 452)
    - Reports (Printed) - Seed Improvement in India, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 453)
    - Reports (Printed) - Seed Processing, Storage, and Distribution Manual, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 454)
    - Reports (Printed) - Seed Production Manual, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 455)
    - Reports (Printed) - Seed Review Team Report, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 456)
    - Seed Monographs - Field Inspection Manual, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 457)
    - Seed Monographs - A Handbook for Seed Inspectors, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 458)
    - Seed Monographs - Indian Minimum Seed Certification Standards, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 459)
    - Seed Monographs - Seed Marketing, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 460)
    - Seed Monographs, 1970, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 461)
      Seed Processing, 1970 Seed Processing Plant Operator's Handbook, 1972
    - Seed Monographs - Seed Storage and Packaging - Applications for India, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 462)
    - Seed Monographs - Seed Testing Manual, 1967 (Box 71, Folder 463)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Sorghum, 1957-1973, n.d.; I4.05
    Correspondence relating to the establishment and organization of the sorghum program appears first within this subseries. Correspondence of a miscellaneous character follows, treating such technical matters as experiment station operations, equipment maintenance, conference and workshop scheduling, training programs, relations with other agricultural organizations, and research programs in seed collection, breeding, entomology and pathology.
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 464)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 465)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 466)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 467)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 468)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 469)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 470)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1957-1969 (Box 72, Folder 471)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1970-1973 (Box 73, Folder 472)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1970-1973 (Box 73, Folder 473)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1970-1973 (Box 73, Folder 474)
    - Correspondence - Bibliography of Sorghum Literature, 1964-1970 (Box 73, Folder 475)
    - Correspondence - "Sorghum: A Bibliogaphy of the World Literature, 1964-69", 1964-1969 (Box 73, Folder 476)
      Manuscript.
    - Correspondence - Breeders' Conference, 1960-1964 (Box 73, Folder 477)
    - Correspondence - Cooperating Agencies and Stations, 1957-1964 (Box 73, Folder 478)
    - Correspondence - Equipment and Supplies, 1957-1965 (Box 73, Folder 479)
    - Correspondence - Equipment and Supplies, 1970-1971 (Box 74, Folder 480)
    - Correspondence - Experiment Stations - Coimbatore, 1962-1968 (Box 74, Folder 481)
    - Correspondence - Experiment Stations - Hyderabad, 1960-1972 (Box 74, Folder 482)
    - Correspondence - Experiment Stations - Kota, 1959-1960 (Box 74, Folder 483)
    - Correspondence - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations - Training Program at IARI, 1970-1971 (Box 74, Folder 484)
    - Correspondence - Germplasm Collection Program, 1957-1967 (Box 74, Folder 485)
    - Correspondence - Germplasm Collection Program, 1957-1967 (Box 74, Folder 486)
    - Correspondence - Germplasm Collection Program, 1957-1967 (Box 74, Folder 487)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project, 1965-1967 (Box 74, Folder 488)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project, 1968-1971 (Box 75, Folder 489)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project, 1968-1971 (Box 75, Folder 490)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project, 1968-1971 (Box 75, Folder 491)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project, 1968-1971 (Box 75, Folder 492)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project - Proposals, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 75, Folder 493)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum and Millets Project - Proposals, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 75, Folder 494)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum Nursery, 1967-1970 (Box 76, Folder 495)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum Workshops - General, 1970-1971 (Box 76, Folder 496)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum Workshops - Publication of Proceedings, 1971-1973 (Box 76, Folder 497)
    - Correspondence - International Sorghum Workshops - Travel Arrangements, 1971-1972 (Box 76, Folder 498)
    - Correspondence - Project for Intensification of Regional Research on Cotton, Oilseeds, and Millets (PIRRCOM), 1957-1967 (Box 76, Folder 499)
    - Correspondence - Project for Intensification of Regional Research on Cotton, Oilseeds, and Millets (PIRRCOM), 1957-1967 (Box 76, Folder 500)
    - Correspondence - Project for Intensification of Regional Research on Cotton, Oilseeds, and Millets (PIRRCOM), 1957-1967 (Box 76, Folder 501)
    - Correspondence - Sorghum Seed Collection, 1958-1972 (Box 77, Folder 502)
    - Correspondence - Sorghum Seed Collection, 1958-1972 (Box 77, Folder 503)
    - Correspondence - Stalk Borer Project, 1959-1960 (Box 77, Folder 504)
    - Correspondence - Trainees, 1967-1968 (Box 77, Folder 505)
    - Interoffice Memoranda, 1957-1961 (Box 77, Folder 506)
    - Interoffice Memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 77, Folder 507)
    - Interoffice Memoranda, 1964-1971 (Box 77, Folder 508)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Progress Reports and Attachments, 1957-1961 (Box 77, Folder 509)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Progress Reports and Attachments, 1957-1961 (Box 77, Folder 510)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Progress Reports and Attachments, 1962-1964 (Box 78, Folder 511)
    - Reports (Printed) - "Catalog of World Collection of Sorghum and Pennisetum," in The Indian Journal of Genetics and Plant Breeding (Vol. 27), December 1967 (Box 78, Folder 0511a)
    - Reports (Printed) - List of Pedigrees of the World Sorghum Collection, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 512)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 513)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 514)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 515)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1961-1967 (Box 79, Folder 516)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1961-1967 (Box 79, Folder 517)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1961-1967 (Box 79, Folder 518)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1961-1967 (Box 79, Folder 519)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968-1971 (Box 80, Folder 520)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968-1971 (Box 80, Folder 521)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1968-1971 (Box 80, Folder 522)
    - Reports (Printed) - Progress Report, 1971-1972 (Box 81, Folder 523)
    - Reports (Printed) - Report on the Systematic Collection of Sorghums, Millets, and Maize... (Box 81, Folder 524)
    - Reports (Printed) - A Special Sorghum Report on Some Characteristics of Hybrid and Parental Variety Performance, 1961 (Box 81, Folder 525)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Wheat, 1965-1973; I4.06
    Correspondence relating to the establishment and organization of the wheat program appears first within this subseries. Correspondence of a miscellaneous character follows, treating such technical matters as experiment station operations, equipment maintenance, conference and workshop scheduling, training programs, relations with other agricultural organizations, and research programs in seed collection, breeding, entomology and pathology.
    Correspondence is typically followed by unpublished and published reports summarizing the results of experimental tests. These reports are arranged alphabetically by title. Filed with unpublished reports are manuscript drafts of reports on various aspects of the research programs. Also present are "trip reports" written by staff from the field. Wheat geneticist R. Glenn Anderson's trip reports on wheat research can be found in Subseries 6.
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 526)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 527)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 528)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 529)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 530)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 531)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 532)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1965-1971 (Box 82, Folder 533)
    - Correspondence - Administration, 1972-1973 (Box 83, Folder 534)
    - Correspondence - Experiment Station - Wellington, 1966 (Box 83, Folder 535)
    - Correspondence - Import of Seed from Mexico, 1965-1971 (Box 83, Folder 536)
    - Correspondence - Import of Seed from Mexico, 1965-1971 (Box 83, Folder 537)
    - Correspondence - Import of Seed Varieties - Winter Wheat, 1969-1970 (Box 83, Folder 538)
    - Correspondence - International Seminar on Change in Agriculture, 1968 (Box 83, Folder 0538a)
    - Correspondence - Teheran (Iran) Conference on Wheat and Barley, 1968 (Box 83, Folder 539)
    - Periodicals - The Farm Quarterly (Reprint), Fall 1967 (Box 84, Folder 540)
    - Periodicals - Indian Journal of Genetics and Plant Breeding (Vol. 31, No. 3), November 1971 (Box 84, Folder 541)
    - Periodicals - Progressive Farming (Vol. VIII, No. 1), September 1971 (Box 84, Folder 542)
    - Periodicals - Studies on Chapati-Making Quality of Wheat, ICAR Technical Bulletin No. 31, March 1971 (Box 84, Folder 543)
    - Periodicals - Wheat Varieties in India, ICAR Technical Bulletin No. 18, February 1968 (Box 84, Folder 544)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - "A Brief Report on Progress Being Made by the Indian Coordinated Wheat Improvement Program," by Norman E. Borlaug, 1966 (Box 84, Folder 545)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - "Indian Wheat Research Designed to Increase Wheat Production," by Norman E. Borlaug, 1964 (Box 84, Folder 546)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - "A Proposal for the Initiation of a Coordinated Wheat Breeding Scheme", 1965 (Box 84, Folder 547)
    - Reports (Manuscript) - Trip Reports - R. Glenn Anderson, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 84, Folder 548)
    - Reports (Printed) - Five Years of Research on Dwarf Wheats, 1968 (Box 84, Folder 549)
    - Reports (Printed) - Lectures and Country Reports Presented at the Second Regional Training Center on Wheat and Barley Breeding, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 550)
    - Reports (Printed) - Minutes of the Fourth All India Wheat Research Workers' Seminar, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 551)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of Agronomy Sub-Committee Wheat Research Workshop, 1968-1969; Volume 1 of 2 (Box 084A, Folder 0551a)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of Agronomy Sub-Committee Wheat Research Workshop, 1968-1969; Volume 2 of 2 (Box 084A, Folder 0551b)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of Agronomy Sub-Committee Wheat Research Workshop, 1968-1969; Volume 1 of 2 (Box 084A, Folder 0551a)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of Agronomy Sub-Committee Wheat Research Workshop, 1968-1969; Volume 2 of 2 (Box 084A, Folder 0551b)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the Fifth All India Wheat Research Workers' Conference, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 552)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the First In-Service Training Course on Wheat Breeding Procedures, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 553)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the Sixth All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 554)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the Seventh All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 555)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the Eighth All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop, 1969; Volume 1 of 2 (Box 86, Folder 556)
    - Reports (Printed) - Proceedings of the Eighth All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop, 1969; Volume 2 of 2 (Box 86, Folder 557)
    - Reports (Printed) - [Proceedings of the] All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop - Volume 4, 1970 (Box 86, Folder 558)
    - Reports (Printed) - [Proceedings of the] All India Wheat Research Workers' Workshop - Volume 5, 1970 (Box 87, Folder 559)
    - Reports (Printed), 1966-1967 (Box 87, Folder 560)
      Proceedings of Wheat Agronomists' Work Conference, 1966 Proceedings of Wheat Agronomists' Workshop, 1967
    - Reports (Printed) - Results of the Coordinated Wheat Trials, 1964-1967 (Box 87, Folder 561)
    - Reports (Printed) - Results of the Coordinated Wheat Trials, 1964-1967 (Box 87, Folder 562)
    - Reports (Printed) - Results of the Coordinated Wheat Trials, 1964-1967 (Box 87, Folder 563)
    - Reports (Printed) - Results of the Coordinated Wheat Trials, 1967-1969 (Box 88, Folder 564)
    - Reports (Printed) - Results of the Coordinated Wheat Trials, 1967-1969 (Box 88, Folder 565)
    - Reports (Printed) - The Rockefeller Foundation Program in Corn and Wheat in Mexico (Reprint), 1969 (Box 88, Folder 566)
    - Reports (Printed) - Speeches Delivered on the Occasion of Norman E. Borlaug's Receipt of the Nobel Peace Prize, Oslo, Norway, 1970 (Box 88, Folder 567)
    - Reports (Printed) - "Wheat Prospects for the Coming Year", 1973 (Box 88, Folder 568)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Miscellaneous IAP Staff Projects, 1963-1972; I4.07
    Records are arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material and thereunder chronologically.
    - Agronomy, 1963-1964 (Box 88, Folder 569)
    - Agronomy, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 570)
    - Agronomy, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 571)
    - Agronomy, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 572)
    - Entomology, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 573)
    - Entomology, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 574)
    - Plant Pathology - General, 1965-1971 (Box 89, Folder 575)
    - Plant Pathology - General, 1965-1971 (Box 89, Folder 576)
    - Plant Pathology - General, 1965-1971 (Box 89, Folder 577)
    - Plant Pathology - Downy Mildew Workshop, 1967-1970 (Box 89, Folder 578)
    - Plant Pathology - Downy Mildew Workshop, 1967-1970 (Box 89, Folder 579)
    - Plant Pathology - Wheat Rust Program, 1968-1971 (Box 90, Folder 580)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Miscellaneous Food, Crops, and Study Programs, 1959-1973; I4.08
    Within this subseries, records are arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material and thereunder chronologically.
    - Barley, 1967, 1969-1971 (Box 90, Folder 581)
    - Beans, 1961-1963 (Box 90, Folder 582)
    - Buckwheat, 1959-1960 (Box 90, Folder 583)
    - Chickpea, 1959, 1961, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 584)
    - Chilies, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 585)
    - Cotton, 1961-1962, 1966-1967, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 586)
    - Date Palms, 1968-1970 (Box 90, Folder 587)
    - Drug Plants - Psyllium, 1968 (Box 90, Folder 588)
    - Fertilizers, 1966-1967, 1969-1971 (Box 90, Folder 589)
    - G-N, 1961-1964 (Box 90, Folder 590)
      Ginger, 1964 Herbicides, 1962-1964 Niger safflower, 1961-1963
    - O-P, 1962-1963, 1968 (Box 90, Folder 591)
      Onion, 1968 Peanuts, 1962-1963
    - Potato Improvement, 1968-1973 (Box 90, Folder 592)
    - Pulses Improvement, 1969-1973 (Box 91, Folder 593)
    - Pulses Improvement - USAID Program, 1968-1973 (Box 91, Folder 594)
    - R, 1952, 1964, 1969-1970 (Box 91, Folder 595)
      Rodent control, 1969-1970 Roses, 1952, 1964
    - Soybean, 1966, 1968-1971 (Box 91, Folder 596)
    - Soybean, 1966, 1968-1971 (Box 91, Folder 597)
    - Sugar Beet, 1970 (Box 91, Folder 598)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - USAID Projects Under Public Law 480, 1959-1971, n.d.; I4.09
    - General Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 91, Folder 599)
    - List of Grants Approved, 1968, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 600)
    - Project Guidelines, 1960 (Box 91, Folder 601)
    - Project Proposals - Agronomy, 1968 (Box 91, Folder 602)
    - Project Proposals - Entomology, 1964, 1968, 1970, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 603)
    - Project Proposals - Maize, 1964 (Box 92, Folder 604)
    - Project Proposals - Plant Pathology, 1968-1969 (Box 92, Folder 605)
    - Project Proposals - Sorghum Projects, 1961-1968, 1971 (Box 92, Folder 606)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs - Miscellaneous Reports, 1961, [1967]-1971; I4.10
    Subseries 10, Miscellaneous Reports, contains reports not associated with a particular crop.
    - All India Coordinated Agronomic Experiments Scheme: Third Annual Workshop, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 607)
    - Annual Progress Report of the Scheme for Studies on Protein, 1968-1969; Volume 1 of 2 (Box 93, Folder 608)
    - Annual Progress Report of the Scheme for Studies on Protein, 1968-1969; Volume 2 of 2 (Box 93, Folder 609)
    - Annual Report of the All India Coordinated Agronomic Experiments Scheme - Volumes 1, 3, 5, 1968-1969 (Box 93, Folder 610)
    - Annual Report of the All India Coordinated Agronomic Experiments Scheme - Volumes 1, 3, 5, 1968-1969 (Box 93, Folder 611)
    - Annual Report of the All India Coordinated Agronomic Experiments Scheme - Volume 6, 1968-1969 (Box 94, Folder 612)
    - Recent Research on the Improvement of Protein and Nutritive Properties of Food..., 1971 (Box 94, Folder 613)
    - "Report of a Feasibility Study on Cooperation among Eastern African Countries in a Regional Cereal Crop Research Program", 1968 (Box 94, Folder 614)
    - Report of the National High Level Scientific Committee for Plant and Animal Introduction and Quarantine, 1971 (Box 94, Folder 615)
      Includes an appendix to the report.
    - "Research Evaluation Report on the Central Island Fisheries Research Station.. .", 1961 (Box 94, Folder 616)
    - A Review (1957-1967) of Cooperative Activities in Research and Education in Agriculture (Box 94, Folder 617)
    - "Studies on Protein Quality of Sorghum, Millet, Wheat, and Other Cereal Grains", 1968 (Box 94, Folder 618)
    - "The Technological Basis for Intensified Agriculture", 1969 (Box 94, Folder 619)
- Indian Agricultural Program - Agricultural Education, 1955-1973, n.d.; I5; 8 __Boxes __2.8 cubic feet
  Series 5, Agricultural Education documents the RF's role in strengthening graduate agricultural education in India. The establishment of state agricultural universities, where Indian scientists could receive training, was deemed central to the success of the Indian Agricultural Program. A twin goal was the creation of a postgraduate school at the Indian Agricultural Research Institute (IARI), which occurred in 1958.
  Series 5, Agricultural Education, has been arranged in two subseries:
  Subseries 1 - General Files
  Subseries 2 - Institutional Files
  See also Subgroup I, Series 6 - Indian Agricultural Program - Agricultural Research Institutes.
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Agricultural Education - General Files, 1955-1973; I5.01
    The role of the IAP's first Field Director, Ralph W. Cummings, in developing academic standards is documented in Subseries 1 by files of the Agricultural Universities Committee (1961-1966). The committee, with Cummings serving as chairman, drew up the guidelines for the establishment of agricultural universities which were later codified in the Model Act for Agricultural Universities (1966). The Model Act with attached correspondence is located in Box 96.
    Subseries 1 includes general correspondence arranged alphabetically by subject.
    Actual dates of this subseries are: 1955-56, 1959-66, 1968, 1970-73.
    - Agricultural Engineering Curriculum, 1961-1964 (Box 95, Folder 620)
    - Agricultural Syllabus Committee of Indian Council on Agricultural Research, 1961-1963 (Box 95, Folder 621)
    - Agricultural Syllabus Committee of Indian Council on Agricultural Research, 1961-1963 (Box 95, Folder 622)
    - Agricultural Universities Committee - Cummings Committee, 1961-1966 (Box 95, Folder 623)
    - Agricultural Universities Committee - Cummings Committee, 1961-1966 (Box 95, Folder 624)
    - Agricultural Universities Committee - Cummings Committee, 1961-1966 (Box 95, Folder 625)
    - Agricultural Universities Committee - Cummings Committee, 1961-1966 (Box 95, Folder 626)
    - Association of Indian Agricultural Universities, 1970-1973 (Box 95, Folder 627)
    - Central Staff College for Agricultural Officers - Proposal, 1961-1963 (Box 96, Folder 628)
    - Central Staff College for Agricultural Officers - Proposal, 1961-1963 (Box 96, Folder 629)
    - Government of India Task Force on International Education, 1965-1966 (Box 96, Folder 630)
    - Historical Materials on Development of Agricultural Education in India, 1955-1956, 1962, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 631)
      Manuscript drafts and printed items.
    - Inspection Team on Post-Graduate Agricultural Education, 1959-1962 (Box 96, Folder 632)
    - Inter-University Board, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 633)
    - Model Act for Agricultural Universities, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 634)
    - University Grants Commission, 1961-1962 (Box 96, Folder 635)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Agricultural Education - Institutional Files, 1957-1973, n.d.; I5.02
    Subseries 2, Institutional Files, contains six boxes of correspondence concerning the establishment and operation of fourteen agricultural universities and their relationship to the various All India Crop Improvement programs. Especially well documented are the Andhra Pradesh Agricultural University (1959-1973), Madhya Pradesh Agricultural University (1961-1973), Mysore University of Agricultural Sciences (1961-1973), Punjab Agricultural University (1959-1973), Rajasthan Agricultural University (1960-1973), and Uttar Pradesh Agricultural University (1957-1973).
    The files in Subseries 2 are arranged alphabetically by educational institution.
    - Andhra Pradesh Agricultural University - Establishment, 1959-1972 (Box 97, Folder 636)
    - Andhra Pradesh Agricultural University - Establishment, 1959-1972 (Box 97, Folder 637)